Emon Roy Bappy

Ahsanullah Hall, BUET Central Road, Dhaka

■ +8801914825156 | ■ emonroy4058@gmail.com | • github.com/Emon4058 | • linkedin.com/in/emon-roy-bappy-7791511b2/

Personal Profile

An undergraduate student at Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology, undertaking Mechanical Engineering major. Enthusiast about Microcontroller based control systems, Electromechanical Systems, and Robotics with two years of experience specializing in printed circuit board design and computer-aided design. Primarily, looking forward to working with soft robotics.

Education

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Sept 2018 - Current

BSc in Mechanical Engineering
Level 4 Term 1, CGPA 3.33/4.00

Notre Dame College

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2016 - 2018

Higher Secondary School Certificate

Sylhet GOVT. Pilot High School

• Group-Science, GPA 5.00/5.00

· General grade scholarship, Dhaka Board

Sylhet, Bangladesh

Secondary School Certificate

• Group-Science, GPA 5.00/5.00

· General grade scholarship, Sylhet Board

2014 - 2016

Work Experience

Team InterplanetarDhaka, Bangladesh

Member, Electrical and Communication Subteam

May 2020 - Present

- Build a Mars Rover capable of traversing through rocky terrain, collecting and processing specimen from environment, performing a variety of tasks.
- Constructed a 6 degree of freedom robotic arm from scratch.
- Technical Skills: Altium PCB Designer, Soldering, Solidworks, Ubuntu, Robot Operating System
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Logical Thinking, Teamwork, Time Management, Communication

Automaestro Dhaka, Banqladesh

Member, Suspension Subteam

Dec 2021 - Present

- Build an automobile model for formula student competition.
- Technical Skills: Solidworks, Ansys Workbench
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

Projects

Hilsha Bot Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology

May 2022 - Sep 2022

- · A bio-inspired underwater electromechanical system, capable of moving like a fish, and controlling its depth.
- An appliance for underwater investigation, marine environment protection, inspection of any underwater construction.

Skills

PCB Design Altium PCB Designer, Proteus, EasyEDA

Simulation Software Ansys Workbench

CAD Solidworks, AutoCAD, Blender

Programming C, Python, Matlab

Robotics Arduino IDE, Robot Operating System **Miscellaneous** Microsoft Office, Ubuntu, धन्X, Git.

Soft Skills Teamwork, Problem-solving, Logical Thinking

1

Achievements

2022	Finalist, University Rover Challenge	The Mars Society
2022	Merit Award, BASIS NATIONAL ICT AWARDS	BASIS
2021	Champion, Sustainable Energy Innovation Challenge	Bikiron
2021	Champion, National Stem Competition	bdSTEM
2021	4th place, 2nd Kibo Robot Programming Challenge National Round	JAXA
2021	Innovation Award, International Planetary Aerial Systems Challenge	Mars Society South Asia
2016	8th position, National Round of 6th Bangladesh Physics Olympiad	BdPh0

Accomplishment

Mechanical Design Solidworks Associate

Dassault Systèmes

Credential ID C-9G7EDFK4NZ

Feb 2022

Languages _____

English Professional proficiency **Bengali** Native proficiency

References _____

Dr. Md. Mahbub Alam

Assistant Professor Department of Chemistry

Bangladesh University of Engineering and technology (BUET)

Email: mdmahbub@chem.buet.ac.bd Website: www.buet.ac.bd/mdmahbub